One of the most important and powerful films of all time!
The Deer Hunter is a drama, war film directed by Michael Cimino.
Three steelworkers enlist in the army and are sent to Vietnam, one
leaving behind a rushed marriage, the others a shared love.
What they encounter during the war changes their lives forever.
Michael Vronsky, played by Robert De Niro.
Nikanor "Nick" Chevotarevich, played by Christopher Walken.
Stan, played by John Cazale.
Steven Pushkov, played by John Savage.
Linda, played by Meryl Streep.
John, played by George Dzundza.
The Deer Hunter is a 1978 American epic war drama film co-written and directed by Michael Cimino about a
trio of Slavic-American steelworkers whose lives are upended by fighting in the Vietnam War.
The soldiers are played by Robert De Niro, Christopher Walken and John Savage, with John
Cazale (in his final role), Meryl Streep and George Dzundza in supporting roles.
The story takes place in Clairton, Pennsylvania (a working-class town on
the Monongahela River south of Pittsburgh) and in Vietnam.
The film is based in part on an unproduced screenplay
called The Man Who Came to Play by Louis A.
Garfinkle and Quinn K.
Redeker about Las Vegas and Russian roulette.
Producer Michael Deeley, who bought the script, hired Cimino, who, with Deric Washburn, rewrote
the script, taking the Russian roulette element and placing it in the Vietnam War.
The film went over budget and over schedule, costing $15 million.
Its production company EMI Films released it in other territories, while Universal
Pictures handled its distribution in the United States and Canada.
The Deer Hunter received acclaim from critics and audiences, with praise for Cimino's direction, the
performances of its cast, its screenplay, realistic themes and tones, and cinematography.
It was also successful at the box office, grossing $49 million.
At the 51st Academy Awards, it was nominated for nine Academy Awards, and won five: Best Picture, Best
Director (for Cimino), Best Supporting Actor (for Walken), Best Sound and Best Film Editing.
It is Meryl Streep's first Academy Award
nomination (for Best Supporting Actress).
The Deer Hunter has been included on lists of the best films ever made, including being named the 53rd-greatest American film of all
time by the American Film Institute in 2007 in their 10th Anniversary Edition of the AFI's 100 Years...100 Movies list.
It was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of
Congress in 1996, as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of vietnam war, vietnam
veteran, small town, suicide, vietnam.
The tone is emotional.